I got eyes on the animal.
♪ Let's all go to the lobby ♪
- ♪ To get ourselves a treat ♪
- Run! Go!
♪ Delicious things to eat ♪
♪ The popcorn can't be beat ♪
♪ The sparkling drinks are just dandy ♪
♪ The chocolate bars and the candy ♪
♪ So let's all go to the lobby
To get ourselves a treat ♪
What?
Let me out!
Keep it steady!
Damn, I don't see it.
Do you see it?
Settle down, kid.
She can't run forever.
Dinosaurs are in our world.
And with every confrontation, we learn
more about this frightening new reality.
How did we get here?
Oh, my God.
It's been three decades since
the deadly events at Jurassic Park,
and we've yet to find a way
for these animals to live safely among us.
After the devastating eruption of
Is la Nublar's long-dormant volcano,
those who survived were
transported to the mainland.
Many of the larger predators were captured,
but the remaining creatures scattered here,
in Big Rock National Park.
While most remained in the wild,
those who made their way to civilization
struggled to adapt
to unfamiliar conditions.
Local authorities have warned
the animals are unpredictable,
and when hungry, extremely violent.
As the dinosaurs spread across borders,
a global black market has risen.
- They're not ours.
- Go on, you sad, pathetic loser!
To combat the growing threat
of illegal poachers,
the US Congress awarded
sole collection rights
to the global giant Biosyn Genetics.
At Biosyn, we're dedicated to the idea
that dinosaurs can teach us
more about ourselves.
CEO Lewis Dodgson has created a sanctuary
in Italy's Dolomite Mountains,
where he hopes to study the dinosaurs'
ancient immune systems
for unique pharmaceutical properties.
While Biosyn believes we can handle
genetic power responsibly,
the public remains skeptical.
Some note these government contracts
have led to massive spikes in Biosyn's profits.
And rumors persist of a human clone
who mysteriously disappeared,
leading to a worldwide search.
Some believe she's genetically identical
to Charlotte Lockwood,
deceased daughter of Jurassic Park
co-founder, Benjamin Lockwood.
Now that we brought these animals
back from extinction,
can we face the consequences?
Are we responsible for them,
or should they be left
to fend for themselves?
As we adapt to an ever-changing world,
we must find answers to these questions,
for their safety as well as for our own.
Let it go!
Hold on!
We are inside the illegal breeding facility.
The juveniles are kept in cages
to keep costs down.
It's medieval.
Claire.
Why do you think
he's separated from the rest?
I don't think he's gonna make it.
No. What are you doing?
We could report this.
The DFW takes days to investigate.
We can save this one now.
It's okay. It's okay, buddy.
Okay. Here we go.
Nope. No!
- Lift.
- Okay.
- Support the head.
- Yeah.
Okay. Yeah.
- Hurry up!
- Check the right side.
- With me.
- Go, go, go.
Okay, come on.
Come on, let's go.
- Hold on!
- To what?
Shit.
Claire, we're gonna get shot!
- No! Claire! No, no, Claire!
- Oh, God.
Oh, shit.
Everybody good?
- No!
Okay. Okay, so I think
we get this one to the DFW,
and then we hit them again.
Yeah. Yeah, you saw
that breeding ground, right?
We're done.
I got a call last week.
It's a real job, something I can do
to effectively change things.
- I gotta take it.
- They need us.
Are you saving these dinosaurs
because they need us,
or are you saving them
to absolve yourself?
- Claire.
- I mean, this is crazy.
Claire,
you're doing the right thing.
But this-- This isn't the way
to go about it anymore.
Honestly, you need someone
who's good at being shot at.
Aren't you and Owen still,
like, a weird thing?
- It's not that weird.
- He didn't mean "weird."
- Mm-mmm.
- No.
Uh, he meant, like, surprising.
Hyah!
Let's bring 'em home!
No.
Okay, come here.
Okay.
Hey, hey.
We're gonna get you some place safe.
Hey.
There you go.
Yeah.
Shit.
Poaching's three to five.
Y'all know that.
Looks like we'll be taking
that animal off your hands.
Like hell you will.
All right. Seems our friend
don't recognize the badge.
Department of Fish and Wildlife.
We're rounding up that dinosaur
for its own safety.
That's funny.
'Cause my friends here,
they typically know all the new recruits.
Shep, do you remember meeting
these guys in orientation or not?
Nope.
Dinosaur bone powder goes for what?
3000 an ounce?
Makes this animal here worth about--
Shoot, $500,000?
How y'all want this to go, huh?
Your bones ain't worth nothing to me.
Hey, brother.
He ain't lying.
I'll see you around.
Never seen you walk away
from a fight before.
Yeah.
I got obligations.
Shouldn't you be in school?
I'm homeschooled.
That so?
And where's home?
I don't know!
Whoa!
Better not stand there, man.
Holy crap.
What in the world, man?
So, the dinosaurs...
Hey.
Where you been?
Nowhere.
What are you burning?
Oh, nothing. Just some old blankets.
You sure you didn't go past the bridge?
That's the look you give me
when you think I'm lying.
- Well, are you?
- No.
Maisie, you're literally looking
everywhere but here.
I said I didn't go past the bridge.
Maisie,
can we start over?
I know, Claire. There are people out there
who'll do anything to find me.
I'm not angry.
- That means you don't have to be angry.
- I'm not angry.
- I can take care of myself.
- Hey.
It's okay for us to depend on each other.
That's what people do.
How would I know what people do?
The only people I've spoken to
in the past four years are you both.
Besides, I'm not even a real person anyway.
- What?
- I was made from someone else.
I'm not me.
You are the only you who ever was.
What?
- N-No.
- Was that, like, really corny?
It was so corny.
- Can we keep that between us?
- Can't promise that.
- Hey, kid.
- Hello.
Sorry I'm late.
Aw.
You smell like horses.
- Mmm.
- Oh, you like that, do ya?
- I do. Yeah.
- Oh.
Okay. Um...
I'm gonna make dinner.
Everything okay?
She went into town again.
Ah, this kid.
Did you talk to her?
I tried.
I'll talk to her.
Slow breaths. Take your time.
Hey. Cut away from yourself.
Whoa!
Wanna know how to win a knife fight?
You gotta let yourself get cut.
Make sure they're cutting
something dispensable
while you're cutting something vital.
And then say something cool like...
"Wrong girl, wrong time."
Wrong girl, wrong time.
Whoo!
- Stone-cold.
- Right?
- I would not mess with her.
- No way.
Listen. We should probably
talk about you going into town.
I don't--
I don't think you understand
how bad it is being trapped here.
You're not trapped here.
We just don't trust people.
No, you just don't trust me.
And then you expect me to trust you.
- Why can't I have any freedom?
- Because you can't.
That went great.
What is happening?
- She's 14.
- Yeah.
You remember what that was like.
I do.
We can't keep her here forever.
If we don't figure this out,
she's gonna go a lot farther than the bridge.
If they find her,
we're never gonna see her again.
We gotta protect her. That's our job.
That's what we're gonna do.
Protect her how?
By locking her inside?
She's got questions.
You know? Questions we can't answer.
She wants to know who she is.
Who Charlotte Lockwood was.
Tracked Grady to his house.
You were right. Raptor's got a juvenile.
But listen, there's something else.
I found that girl you've been after.
Here you go.
Thanks for coming.
Wasn't sure who to call.
Fish and Wildlife didn't even
want to see it if it wasn't a dinosaur.
Yeah, well,
they get all the attention.
You guys want to vary
the sampling plots
a hundred yards each?
These your students?
Yeah. We've been looking into the impact
of industrial farming on the environment.
So, this is right up our alley.
They hit 60 fields in the county.
You seen anything like this before?
No. Not like this.
They've been leaving degraded fields
all across the Midwest.
First these big companies
try to kill off all the insects, now this.
Is that your land?
That's the Bennetts' corn.
The locusts didn't eat that.
You plant the same seed
as the Bennetts?
No.
We're independent.
They use Biosyn seed.
Yeah, I bet they do.
You say you caught a live one?
Kids, this is Dr. Ellie Sattler.
She's a scientist from the university.
A bug scientist?
Uh, sort of.
I study plants from a long time ago,
and that helps me figure out
how to protect plants and soil now.
Wow. Look at that.
Pretty cool, huh?
This is called a field sequencer,
and it helps me read DNA
everywhere I am.
I'm gonna put this swab in his mouth.
Good job.
And now, I need to take
your little buddy on a road trip.
Where are you taking it?
I need a second opinion.
- Hey, Madeline?
- Yeah?
We just gotta clean out
this little cylinder.
Okay. Let her down slow.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Easy.
Let's start padding that other side.
Just about there. I'm on it.
Why do we dig?
Because paleontology is science,
and science is about the truth.
And there is truth in these rocks.
Stop.
It says here that the T. Rex
had a tiny brain.
Well, it turns out that T. Rex
was way smarter than we thought.
Capable of memory, of loyalty.
That's a T. Rex.
They've been around since,
like, the '90s.
I don't get why we're here
digging up bones.
It just seems kinda random.
Right.
Grant!
You're gonna want to see this.
Guys, can you help me?
I'll pack it out.
I'll make sure nobody else crosses it.
Ellie Sattler.
Alan Grant.
You look the same.
And this place, it's so...
so, uh... you.
I'm sorry.
If I'd known you were coming, I would've...
Uh...
Can I get you something?
A beer or...
Um, well, maybe not at 10:00 a.m.,
but iced tea or--
Tea. Yeah.
Tea. I can do that.
Saw a lot of tourists on the way in.
Well, the funding's dried up,
so somebody's gotta pay for all this.
Right. Thank you.
I read your articles about soil science
and regenerative farming.
That's great.
Thanks.
Gave me grounds
for some hope for a change.
And the one about growing algae.
Mmm! Alan, it's amazing.
It's a totally viable carbon-neutral fuel.
It's incredible. Our answers are
in our oceans and in our soil.
Sure, it's gonna take work,
but we're on the verge of extinction.
My God. What are we gonna do?
Just sit around?
Not on my watch.
What?
No, nothing. I just...
Just like listening to you is all.
So, you're here on your own?
Yeah, yeah. On my own.
How are your kids?
Mmm.
Amazing. Grown. It's shocking.
They're both in college.
Can you believe that?
And Mark?
It's over.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
It's okay.
I'm back to me.
And my work. You know, it's...
That's great.
It's good. It is. I'm alone at last.
Exciting times.
Yeah, I'm living the Alan Grant life.
- It's just...
- Can be lonely.
...so freeing.
Ellie.
You didn't come out all this way
just to catch up, now, did you?
Well, that's a locust.
Mandibles, wings, thorax, but--
God, the size of it is massive.
It has genes that have been extinct
since the Cretaceous.
And swarms of them are
decimating crops from Iowa to Texas.
Terrifying, right?
Started as a few hundred.
There could be millions
by the end of the summer.
If they keep going, there'll be
no grain to feed chickens, cattle.
The entire food chain would collapse.
Well, it's clearly designed,
but why would anyone do that?
None of the crops
they're eating are Biosyn seed.
Biosyn.
You're saying Biosyn made this?
I mean, it would not shock me that they
wanna control the world's food supply.
Not before a few million starve.
Yeah, what is that saying?
How we're three meals away from anarchy?
If we don't stop them,
you can pick your last three meals.
So, why are you bringing it to me?
I need concrete evidence
Biosyn's responsible for all this.
I need to go to their sanctuary
and get DNA from another locust there.
But I need a witness.
Alan.
You command respect.
People believe you.
Ellie.
You know why I'm here.
It's quiet. I'm done with all that.
Are you? Okay.
Well, I'm sorry, Alan.
Nobody gets that luxury anymore,
not even you.
And you know what?
You're the one I trust.
This Biosyn sanctuary is, what,
a hundred miles from anywhere?
How do you even get in there?
I got an invite from their
in-house philosopher.
Seems there's a lot of money
in being a chaotician these days.
And he just happened
to invite you out of the blue?
He said there were things I'd wanna see.
Uh-huh.
You coming or what?
It's clear!
Keep it going. That's good.
Every animal captured on the mainland
comes through here
before shipping out
to Biosyn's sanctuary in the Dolomites.
We give them medical attention
and make sure they leave healthy.
So much security.
Those are just the ones you see.
A lot of shady types out there
want these guys.
- Hey.
- Your plane's just fueling up.
Biosyn's a tough invite.
You guys must know somebody.
- Do you mind if I--
- Of course.
Hello.
You see me?
You follow me.
We rescued these guys
from an illegal breeding farm
in Nevada a few weeks ago.
Shut the whole place down.
Anonymous tip.
Good girl. Yes. Yes.
Alan. You never get used to it.
Okay. We're good. Close it up!
- Take care.
- Thank you. Bye.
Okay.
Hey.
You look just like Blue.
This?
You wanna try it?
Okay.
Huh.
Maisie, don't move.
Hey, girl.
Staying out of trouble?
She had a baby. That's impossible.
- Back up.
- She won't hurt us, right?
You're damn right she will.
Just breathe.
- If you don't, she'll think you're scared.
- I am scared.
Nah. She doesn't need to know that.
Her nest has got to be nearby.
Maisie, get inside.
- I'm coming with you.
- What did I just say?
- We gotta move.
- Not yet. We need the girl.
Hey, what's up?
Wow.
Maisie?
Mm-mmm. Mm-mmm.
Where you going?
You can't keep me here.
You're not my mother.
She's leaving the house.
Get in the truck!
Come on! Let's go!
Got it!
- Tie it down!
- Hold on.
Come on. Let's go!
- Get in!
- Come on!
Let's get out of here.
Who are you?
Claire!
They found her.
What? Who are they?
Poachers. I've seen them around.
Leader's a real shit-heel.
He must have recognized me,
followed me here.
- Where is she?
- Go get the truck.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
- Owen!
- Hey. No.
They took her kid too.
I am gonna get her back.
I promise you that.
Come on.
I know who to call.
Please, please! No, no!
This year, man.
What's next?
Historically?
Uh, darkness, blood, rain of fire.
I think frogs.
We're not gonna be around
for much longer anyway.
These locusts in Nebraska
are about to wrap it up.
They're eating the corn, wheat.
Basically all of our food
and our food's food.
So, we can say goodbye to this.
Hello?
Franklin. It's me.
You at work?
Okay, you're kind of a subject
of interest around here,
so I can't really be talking to you.
Come on. I'm in trouble.
I really need your help. Please.
Yeah, and I could lose my job,
and you know I'm not qualified
to do anything else.
We're outside.
Let me talk to him.
- That him?
- That's him.
Name's Rainn Delacourt.
Real piece of work.
What'd he take?
Something we care about very much.
Oh, shit. I told you somebody
would come looking for her.
You can't just take a person, Claire.
- We had no choice.
- Not in the eyes of the law.
This guy is not the law.
Tell us how to find him.
Where'd you call me from?
We have a man on the inside
of Delacourt's operation.
There's an exchange in Malta
sometime tomorrow. Cash for cargo.
Was she with him?
There's no mention,
but we have people on the ground already.
One of them you know.
A lot of us got recruited by the CIA
after the park went down.
Barry's French intelligence now.
I need to talk to him.
You can't just call him.
He's deep cover.
Look, once we make the bust in Malta,
our guys will see
if Delacourt knows where she is.
Our guys. Not you.
Promise me you won't go in there
with your vest and mess everything up.
Why would I do that?
Look, you guys are both crazy,
but you seem like you're good parents,
or whatever you're trying to be.
She's lucky to have you.
Don't get killed, okay?
I think we're almost there.
Yeah.
Dr. Sattler. Dr. Grant.
- Ramsay Cole, Communications.
- Oh, hey.
I have to warn you,
everyone's so excited to have you.
You guys are absolute legends
around here.
Mmm. You must be confusing us
with somebody else.
You know, it's great that you guys
are still so close with Dr. Malcolm.
I mean, sometimes you meet your heroes
and they disappoint you,
but he's exactly the way
you'd want him to be.
I mean, such motility of thought.
It's incredible.
How much time
have you spent with him?
Uh, well, I know that was sarcastic,
but honestly, not enough.
Oh, please. After you.
And watch your head.
Biosyn bought this land
for the amber deposits back in the '90s.
But we've managed to turn it
into a safe haven
for about 20 displaced species.
First generation came from Sorna.
Most of the Nublar dinosaurs are here too.
Took Fish and Wildlife three years
to catch the T. Rex.
- The--
- The T. Rex is here?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Arrived just before you guys.
Aerial deterrent system, active.
Restricted air space.
Protects the airborne life.
Keeps the pterosaurs below 500 feet.
Airborne?
Is that Dreadnoughtus?
What?
Beautiful, right?
The name means "fear nothing."
Well, I guess you know that.
- What do they graze on?
- Hawthorn and fern.
All indigenous. Nothing stocked
except for the deer population.
It's a great mezzanine species
for the apex predator.
The apex predator?
Giganotosaurus.
At least for now.
You don't let people in there, right?
Uh, no. Our-- Our research--
Our research outposts are connected
completely underground.
If we have to,
we can just herd the animals remotely
using a neuro-implant that sends
electrical signals directly to the brain.
Like shocks?
Uh... n-no, like signals.
Doesn't it strike you as a little bit...
- Cruel?
- Cruel.
Do you know how much voltage was
in the electric fences at Jurassic Park?
Yeah.
Please join Dr. Ian Malcolm
at noon in the lecture hall
for the Ethics of Genetic Power.
God, everyone's so young.
Well, it is part of our ethos
to attract the best and brightest.
Doctors.
Respected, renowned Dr. Sattler.
Dr. Grant. Hi.
Wow, this is big. I'm Lewis.
- Dodgson. Yeah.
- Hi.
- You're Lewis Dodgson?
- I am. How do you do?
We didn't expect
to actually see you here.
Well, I wouldn't be anywhere else.
- Would you?
- No.
I mean, the people you see here
are changing the world.
Would you mind if we, um...
- Just to-- it would mean a lot.
- Oh.
Do you wanna, um...
- Oh, great. Thank you so much.
- Oh.
- That's good. That's good. Thanks.
- Okay.
So, you are going to see
some remarkable things today.
We are unlocking
the true power of the genome.
We're this close. Believe me.
You'll make a fortune with that.
No, it's not about money.
No, we've already identified dozens
of applications for paleo-DNA.
We're talking about cancer,
Alzheimer's, autoimmune.
We will be saving lives.
- But... shh.
- I bet.
Um, anyway, I wish I could take you
around myself, but, uh, it's--
So, you're in more-than-capable
hands with Ramsay.
He's basically a young me.
Only smarter and, uh, taller.
Do you have food?
- Like, one of my bars?
- Pardon? Um...
No, never mind.
I-I'll find something.
So, I want to do more of this later on,
if we, um...
Oh! We booked you a private pod...
- Right.
- ...for the trip out, so--
It's beautiful. You'll love it.
Through the caverns and everything.
You better hurry. Malcolm's on.
He's a bit of a contrarian,
but I like him.
He keeps us on our toes. Anyway.
Thank you for being here. It's--
Okay. Um, follow me, please.
What?
Human beings have
no more right to safety or liberty
than any other creature
on this planet.
We not only lack dominion over nature,
we're subordinate to it.
And now, here we are
with the opportunity
to rewrite life at our fingertips.
And just like nuclear power,
nobody knew what to expect
with genetic engineering,
but they pressed the button
and hoped for the best,
just like you are doing now.
Yep. You.
You control the future
of our survival on planet Earth.
According to you,
the solution is genetic power.
But that same power
could devastate the food supply,
create new diseases,
alter the climate even further.
Unforeseen consequences occur.
And every time, every single time...
we all act surprised?
Because deep down,
I don't think that any of us actually
believe that these dangers are real.
In order to instigate
revolutionary change,
we must transform human consciousness.
Whoo!
Yeah!
- Mayam?
- Dr. Malcolm?
Very good. There you go.
I don't want to be rude to my friends.
Thank you.
Catch me on my way out.
Thanks, everybody.
Look at you,
and look at me, and look at you.
Wha-- This is so trippy.
You look like you're doing well.
Well, I got five kids, you know,
whom I adore more than life itself, so...
expenses add up.
You? Alan, are you--
You have any family or...
- No.
- So, I need to talk to you.
Yeah, I need to talk to you too.
Privately.
Do you two talk a lot?
- He slid into my DMs.
- He did what?
- It's urgent, Ian.
- What did you do?
Seven minutes to midnight stuff.
The Doomsday Clock
might be about out of time,
but, as they say, it's always darkest
just before eternal nothingness.
What?
Locusts altered with Cretaceous-era DNA.
- That's not my field.
- But if these things continue to multiply,
we're talking about cascading
system-wide effects, Ian.
Gosh, that's a drag.
- What is the matter with you?
- "Drag"?
Why, is there something special
you wanted me to do?
- How about give a damn?
- You know too much not to care.
Hey, I gave my opinion
robustly for years.
As expected, the sum of our human
endeavors has led to our annihilation,
and the only play now is to take
the time we have left and, uh...
you know, just like we always do,
squander it.
Honestly, Ian, that's bullshit.
Can I offer you guys some joe?
Tyler, please, two cappuccinos.
I don't want a cappuccino.
I could do, like,
a cortado or macchiato--
Trust me, it's real tough, that jet lag.
This is gonna perk you right up.
The locusts are part of a larger project
called Hexapod Allies.
- I--
- You're right about their intent.
I started hearing rumors
six weeks ago.
I read your piece on decadence
and put two and two together.
- I was not raising my voice.
- You're beginning to. It's crescendoing.
They're proliferating wildly.
They're lasting three,
four times longer than they should.
And all my models are pointing toward
a global ecological collapse, Ian.
Downstairs, sublevel six.
That's where they keep the locusts.
Look for a lab marked L4.
But wait, how are we
gonna get down there?
This looks so silky.
May I touch this blouse, by any chance?
Sure.
You know what it is?
Don't tell me. This is...
- You won't know it.
- ...sustainable bamboo.
- It is sustainable bamboo.
- That's why I said--
- How'd you know?
- I just know.
- It's amazing.
- Very amazing.
I've got cumin, cinnamon.
I've got allspice,
which is not very popular.
- I've got five-spice...
- Doctor.
...if you're into that kind of feel.
- Um, and let's talk milks.
- Yeah.
Okay, soy milk, yes?
- No.
- What just happened?
We're in.
Sublevel six. Restricted.
Lewis, you're not listening to me.
The locusts' prehistoric DNA has
made them stronger than they should be.
They're multiplying like crazy
and they're not dying.
- What part of this don't you understand?
- I do understand.
This is gonna be a global famine.
Hey, hey,
we can't anticipate everything.
We need to eradicate
the ones we released.
- What?
- All of them.
- No. No.
- Like--
- Henry, we don't want to cause a panic.
- Like yesterday.
We want control.
There's no such thing.
When we're afraid,
what do we do?
What have we done before?
We follow through.
That's what we do.
Right?
Right.
We found the girl.
She's en route.
- Cost me a fortune.
- What?
- Wait, you found her?
- Yeah, found them both.
Her and the little raptor.
Blue reproduced all on her own,
just like you said.
You're so smart, Henry.
That's why this works.
You understand the value
of these creatures.
You always have.
I do too.
We don't stop because of a, what,
little side project went south?
Hey, if they trace the locusts back to us,
they come for the dinosaurs.
All your work, gone.
Billions of dollars in assets, gone.
Diamonds with no one to mine them.
You really think she's the solution?
Okay.
Everything involving the girl
goes through me, right?
Is she all right?
She better be.
She's the most valuable
intellectual property on the planet.
I said I'd call you.
They land yet?
Second plane is incoming.
- Who said anything about a second plane?
- We flew them separately.
I'm not taking any chances.
And we'll need payment before delivery.
I didn't like what happened last time.
Okay. Okay, just call me when it's done.
You said I was going some place safe.
You are.
- Walk to the car.
- No.
It's not a choice.
Fifty grand to fly one little raptor.
Not bad.
What's with the girl?
Not your problem.
Pleasure doing business.
We're ready. Let's go.
Owen.
Hi, Claire.
I thought you would've chosen
a quieter line of work.
I tried. My cousin and I opened a café.
I lasted three weeks.
The way the world is headed,
it's hard to look away.
Delacourt was hired by Soyona Santos,
a broker in the underground
dinosaur trade.
We don't have intel on his cargo,
but once they make the exchange,
we'll see what they know about your girl.
You can listen in,
but promise me you will not make contact.
No.
There is a big underground market
for dinosaurs now.
Europe, Middle East, northern Africa,
it all comes through here.
Don't look at anyone,
don't talk to anyone.
Just try to blend in.
I'm okay.
Still flying for Santos, huh?
You must need money.
What's it to you?
I've got cargo.
A thousand kilos of dinosaur to Palermo.
Lystrosaurus. Very rare.
I give you two thousands.
Eight.
He may be ugly, but he's got spirit.
- What are you gonna do with him?
- He's mine now. What do you care?
Yeah! Come on, man!
Yes!
You lost?
You're American.
And that make us friends?
- Listen, I just got here and--
- Oh, no.
That was not an invitation. Here.
Souvenir.
Go back to the hotel, you know,
throw some bath salts in a bath.
This place, not your vibe.
Wait.
- Look.
- Claire.
Claire.
I know this must feel exotic,
but if you mess with the wrong person
down here, you disappear.
You feel me?
Good luck, okay?
Wait.
- Wait.
- What is this?
- I need your help.
- I don't know you.
- I'm looking for someone.
- Don't do that.
She is all alone. Please.
- That your daughter?
- Yes.
Sorry, I can't get involved.
- Think I got him.
- Target on the move.
That's our undercover agent with him.
Claire, he's headed underground.
- You see him?
- Yeah, I've got him.
All right, let's go.
Team four,
need you to sweep spreading south.
Come on!
All units, take up bull's-eye position.
This is Bravo One.
Primary target in sight.
No sign of the girl.
Alpha team, stand clear.
My people say the raptor arrived
in good condition.
You boys didn't cock this up.
Color me amazed.
I do have another job for you.
Short hop, money's double.
What's the cargo?
Atrociraptors.
Thoroughbreds.
Trained to kill.
- Kill who?
- Whoever they're told.
Laser marks the target, they attach
to the scent, don't stop till it's dead.
Inescapable.
Those idiots making hybrids
had it all wrong.
You can't engineer loyalty.
You have to nurture it.
50,000 to fly them to Riyadh.
In or out?
She's not here.
Where are we going?
Almost there.
- That's the drop, let's go!
- Need eyes on...
Weapons down! Eyes on them!
Hands in the air! Contact made!
Delacourt, on the floor now!
Get on the ground!
Delacourt! Stay with him!
Shit.
Get that truck out of here!
There goes Santos!
Damn, we lost Delacourt.
This is Bravo One.
Truck is approaching the underpass.
Go.
Man, come on! Roll it!
The girl, where is she?
Where did they take her?
- Get it off!
- Where is she?
I don't know!
We handed her off to Santos.
I don't know where
they took her after that.
Claire, it's Santos,
the woman in white.
I'll find her.
- Spread out.
- Bravo team, watch your six.
- Hey, hey! Hey!
- Hold it!
- Let them out.
- What?
You heard me.
Merde.
Claire, do you have her?
- We had some trouble.
- What kind?
The parents, Grady and Dearing.
They're here.
- Can you take care of it?
- Not for free.
Well, do it.
Okay, okay. Listen.
Oh!
No, no, no!
You don't use it on people.
Where's my daughter?
She wasn't yours to begin with.
Tell me.
Biosyn.
They're taking her to Biosyn.
You missed her.
She's gone.
Take my hand. Come on.
Hold on tight.
What?
Do you remember how we
used to get the raptors in the truck?
- Yeah.
- You're up.
- No.
At the last minute, dive roll.
- I don't dive roll.
- You'll be fine.
I never got the timing right.
- Now?
- Any minute. Any minute now.
- No.
Now!
Yeah. Yeah, yeah!
Freeze!
I'm flying us out of here.
Tell me where you wanna be dropped.
You ever flown to Biosyn?
Owen! They took her to Biosyn.
There's an airfield
on the north side of the island.
Go.
You're under arrest.
Stay where you are.
Right!
Heads up!
We made a lot of enemies today.
We gotta go.
- He'll be here.
- Uh-huh.
Out of time, out of time.
There he is.
- Pull over.
- That's not how planes work.
Open the back.
Come on!
Hold on tight!
Oh, sh--
Still got it.
Are you-- Are you hurt?
- Are you okay? You hurt?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Where? Where are you hurt?
- Yeah.
- Where are you hurt?
- No, no. I'm okay. I'm okay.
Are you okay? What--
- Arm hurts pretty bad. Is it bleeding?
- Are you all right?
I don't know.
Am I? Am I?
Let me see.
- Is it-- Is it cut?
- No. No.
No, you're okay.
- Okay.
- You're okay.
Kayla Watts.
You're welcome.
You don't look like you fly for Biosyn.
I'm gonna take that the way you meant it
and not the way it sounded.
I fly for whoever got a bag,
but we'll call this one a favor.
Those don't work. They broke.
I'll take you all to Biosyn,
but I can't promise it won't be dangerous.
You're willing to risk your life
for people you never met?
You wanna ask questions,
or you want a ride?
We'll take the ride.
So this is our habitat
development lab.
A lot of exciting discoveries
as of late.
We've brought back numerous species
in their purest form,
and I mean complete, untouched genomes,
like Moros intrepidus.
- What?
- Yeah.
Wow.
What about splicing DNA?
You know, creating new species.
Oh, no, Dr. Sattler,
we don't do that here.
We like to think we're more evolved.
Looks like we still have
some time left before your ride.
Uh, would you guys like to tour
the facilities yourselves?
Oh, uh, I mean, we could.
- Yeah, why not?
- Great.
I'll meet you guys at the hyperloop,
station three in about 30 minutes.
Elevators are down this hall,
not those.
Those lead you down to the sublevels.
You need special clearance
to get down there.
- Oh, okay.
- Thirty minutes.
Here. Take this.
Okay?
Yep.
I'm really sorry
that it had to happen this way.
Yep, that's what kidnappers say.
Claire should never have
hidden you away.
You're way too important, Maisie.
You took her too?
Yeah.
We needed her
to help us understand you.
Hey, Beta.
You okay?
Did you say "Beta"? Is that her name?
I gave it to her.
Beta is pretty special.
You know, when we made Blue,
we used monitor lizard DNA
to fill in the gaps in her genome.
Monitor lizards can reproduce
without a mate.
So Beta and Blue
are genetically identical,
and that's what they have
in common with you and--
Charlotte.
What do you know about Charlotte?
She died.
A long time ago.
It broke my grandpa's heart.
So he made me.
No, Maisie. Actually, he didn't.
Charlotte made you.
I'm so excited for everyone to see
what we've been doing here.
There's new technology being made,
new science, like, every day almost.
And it's great to be in the center of--
center of that.
Charlotte lived on Site B
with all of us till the storm.
She loved dinosaurs.
- Charlotte, be careful.
- Yeah, I will.
She grew up around scientists.
And eventually...
she became one herself.
A butterfly flew into
my office this morning.
They say tiny things have huge impacts,
and I agree wholeheartedly.
She was brilliant.
For all my work with creatures,
wings flapping...
In ways that I'll never be.
In the metaphysics of identity,
can a replica truly be the original?
And if it's possible, what makes it so?
I've lost my pen.
Is that me?
Yeah.
Just like Blue, Charlotte was able
to have a child all by herself.
She created you with her own DNA.
So I do have a mother.
Your grandfather didn't want
anyone to know the truth.
He was protecting her, and you.
And we're the same?
You were.
When you were a baby, Charlotte started
to show symptoms of a genetic disorder.
That's how she died.
She didn't know she had it
until after you were born.
- Do I have it too?
- No.
She changed your DNA.
She altered every cell in your body
to eradicate this disease.
No one on earth has
ever known how to do that.
She fixed me.
Charlotte's discovery
is a part of you now.
Your DNA could change the world.
And I have to know how she did it,
but I just can't replicate her work.
If I could just study you and Beta,
whose DNA was never changed, I could...
fix a terrible mistake that I've made.
What kind of mistake?
Sublevel six. Restricted.
Thanks for coming.
- Which lab did Malcolm say?
- L4.
This is it.
Okay. Get in,
get the sample and get out.
And move slow.
They can swarm
at the slightest disturbance.
Orthoptera.
Two weeks.
Fully mature. This one.
Ready? Easy.
Okay. Go.
What?
Go get it.
Is that necessary?
Wh-What did you think
was gonna happen?
I have to take a sample.
We need concrete evidence. This is it.
Alan, you said there was no time.
Can you get it?
Of course I can get it.
Okay. Easy.
Watch its legs.
Ugh. Yech.
Here we go.
They're cell signaling between them.
This is not good, Ellie.
I almost got it.
How does she remain an asset, Henry,
if you're incriminating both of us
by showing her classified things
on the computer?
Charlotte Lock wood believed
the methods used at Jurassic Park
could cure disease.
She was right.
Having filled the gaps
in Maisie's genome with altered DNA,
she used a pathogen to deliver
the repaired sequence to every cell.
If I can repurpose what she did,
I could change the locust DNA,
eradicating them in a single generation.
Maisie and the baby raptor
will provide the missing data.
Hey, do you wanna get out of here?
What the--
Got it.
Oh, my God!
They're everywhere! Help me!
Oh, God! No!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Maisie.
Asset containment breach.
Please remain at your stations.
Oh, my God.
- Oh, God. I can't see!
- Where's the key?
Oh, God!
You okay?
Yeah. You?
Yeah.
Oh.
You're Dr. Ellie Sattler and Alan Grant.
You were at Jurassic Park.
What are you doing here?
What? What--
I'm Maisie Lockwood.
Uh, hey, we don't, uh...
We're not--
We don't work for Biosyn.
I can tell.
- We gotta get out of here.
- Yeah, we should go.
Okay. In and out.
We find your girl and go.
Tower, this is N141.
Request to land for freight delivery. Over.
N141, negative.
We've been advised you're carrying
unauthorized passengers. Over.
Copy that, Tower.
Be advised shipment is perishable.
We need immediate clearance.
It's an emergency. Over.
There isn't-- No.
Negative.
Return to point of origin.
You seem to be breaking up.
Are you hearing me on your side?
May need to check systems.
Nice try, Kayla.
They will down your bird.
Who is this?
Is this Denise?
You do not want me to start spilling secrets, Denise.
You remember Dubrovnik.
She's--
Different Denise, in accounts.
Talked to Santos.
It's the girl's parents.
Let's shut off the ADS.
Are you sure?
Uh-huh.
What's that?
Uh...
That's the, uh--
That's the Aerial Deterrent System.
- Keeps the airborne life away.
- Why is it blinking?
Deadass Denise in the tower
just turned it off.
We gotta get out of this airspace
right now.
- That's another plane, right?
- Not exactly.
- Is that a--
- Quetzalcoatlus.
Late Cretaceous,
should have stayed there.
Okay. Okay.
It's cool. We're good.
It's gone.
This plane is going down!
If you're gonna eject,
you need to do it now!
- I only got one chair, and she's in it.
- You don't have parachutes?
I wasn't expecting company!
Claire! We gotta get you off this plane.
What?
The parachute is gonna
open automatically.
If it doesn't, you pull this lever.
Do you understand me?
Claire!
If it doesn't open automatically,
you're gonna pull
this lever behind you. Okay?
Ten thousand feet!
Hey, you're the one
who's gotta go to get to her.
You're her mom.
You're her only shot.
I'll see you again.
I love you.
What's the plan?
Whatever happens. That's the plan.
- Three.
- This way.
- Alan, we need the code.
- Let's try this thing.
Yeah.
Get down.
- Thank God it's you!
- I know.
- This place is a maze.
- Good you're here.
We were so confused.
I thought we were lost.
Then you said station three.
And I was like, here--
Do you have the sample?
- What?
- What are you talking about?
The DNA sample. Do you have it?
Biosyn's responsible
for the locust epidemic.
Dodgson's covering it up.
You were right.
I'm here to help you.
Do you have it?
Yeah.
Good.
This pod will take you
to the airfield.
We have a plane ready to fly.
- Ian told you about Hexapod Allies?
- No.
I told him.
What?
- Okay. You guys gotta go.
- Wait.
Maisie.
Maisie Lockwood.
Go.
Okay.
That was my baby.
Okay, okay.
Where'd you learn to fly?
Uh, Air Force.
Legacy on my mama's side.
Yeah. I'm Navy.
Okay, so how'd you end up doing this?
I was a legit contract pilot for a grip,
but it didn't exactly pay enough
to be out here sending money home.
So I hit up a few contacts
for the more lucrative shady shit.
Honestly, I might be done
with this line of work.
Is that why you're helping us?
I was there when they
handed your girl off to Biosyn.
I could have said something,
but I didn't.
And when I saw her picture--
It isn't enough to do nothing.
Thank you.
No.
Nope.
What an asshole.
You good?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I'm not shook at all. You?
Nah. Nah, no.
Ejection seat beacon.
We'll find her.
Okay, okay.
You really love her, huh?
Yeah.
I get it.
I like redheads too.
What? God.
- Who is that?
- It's Grant and Sattler.
- Is this live?
- Twelve minutes ago.
We were tracking the escaped asset.
My guys missed it.
They stole a DNA sample.
How'd they get in there?
They used an access key.
Yankee White clearance.
One of our cameras saw Ian Malcolm
put something in Sattler's pocket.
All right.
I want to see him.
And get Ramsay up here too, will you?
- Where are they now?
- On the way to the airfield.
They caught the hyperloop
right on schedule.
How are you?
You all right?
Not really, no.
Hey.
I, uh, knew your mom.
You did?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, a few years after Hammond died,
she came to my university to lecture,
and we became good friends.
What was she like?
Brilliant.
Light-years ahead of everybody else.
And she had a conscience.
While they were out
building theme parks,
well, she was determined to prove
that genetic power could save lives.
And I was her experiment.
No.
She wanted a child
more than anything.
But she wanted you to have
what she couldn't.
A full life.
I didn't know her long,
but I know she loved you very much.
What's happening?
This must be the old amber mines.
We're inside the mountain.
They must've made access doors
when they built these tunnels.
You ready?
I'm good.
No, that's not reasonable.
You want to go into the dark tunnel.
I want to stay in the bulletproof tube.
Who's being unreasonable?
But the bulletproof tube has no door.
Look, uh...
I know how you feel.
It's... It's scary. It is.
But trust me, moving forward
is better than staying still.
And Dr. Sattler here is
a good person in a tight spot,
and this is a tight spot.
So, you coming?
All right.
Hey, I heard the alarm.
Everything all right?
Yeah. No, no.
Nothing we can't, uh, handle. Listen--
- You rang?
- Oh, good.
Dr. Malcolm, you are...
- fired.
- What?
It was such a cushy gig.
You can give your access key
to security if you still have it.
One of the hyperloop pods
just shut down in the amber mines.
What?
Wow. This day.
Uh, which-- Which pod are we--
Are there, um...
dinosaurs in the mines?
There are dinosaurs everywhere.
Technically, birds are dinosaurs,
g-genetically speaking at least.
Okay.
Lewis, Grant and Sattler are in this pod.
- We need to send a security team ASAP.
- Absolutely, Ramsay. Thank you.
Let's all just stay in our lanes though.
We can take care of it.
Thank you, Doctor.
That's it, huh?
Nothing else to see here?
Uh, I'm not sure
I admire your tone right now.
- You need to leave.
- Yeah, I do.
But first,
I owe all these folks an apology.
I think that by lending my cachet
to this joint,
I might've made it seem
as if Biosyn wasn't rotten to the core.
That's enough, Ian.
See, here's how they get you.
They give you so many promotions
in a short period of time
that it bludgeons your capacity
for critical thinking.
Oh, my God.
Then there are doors that you don't open,
things that you ignore.
But mainly, he's exploiting
your enchantment with these.
Is there an actual concern here,
or are you just--
You're racing toward the extinction
of our species, and you don't care.
You know exactly what you're doing,
but you won't stop.
You can't.
I thought you might be different,
but you're just like everyone else.
You see what you want to see.
You imagine unchecked avarice,
so that's what you find.
You envision, what,
an evil, unbound Prometheus,
- so that's what I am to you?
- Prometheus got gored.
So will you, you rapacious rat bastard.
Ramsay, will you help
Dr. Malcolm gather his things?
His room, and then to the airfield.
That's it.
Dodgson.
Allosaurus?
Giganotosaurus.
Largest known terrestrial carnivore.
He put two apex predators in one valley.
Pretty soon there's only gonna be one.
Did you feel that?
That's an air current.
Must be an opening up ahead.
How old is this mine, do you think?
Just breathe.
Nobody panic.
Just watch out for bats.
- Who said anything about bats?
- I hate bats.
Well, there's probably no bats.
No falling rocks.
Just a possibility of toxic gas,
dehydration, hypothermia.
Just possibilities, nothing for certain.
I should've left you where you were.
Why did I bring you into this?
- You were happy in your element.
- What? What? Ellie.
What?
I wasn't happy.
You weren't?
- Do you guys have kids?
- What?
Uh... no. I-I do. Two.
But not with him?
Uh... no.
No, just old friends.
Uh, just old friends.
Really?
Won't be long before
security knows you're gone.
A map. That looks like an old map.
You don't have a new map?
There's an access gate
at the northeast corner of the mine.
- If your friends make it out--
- If?
- When they make it out.
- Yes, sir.
That's where they'll be.
These roads are protected, right?
Uh, yeah, I'd drive fast.
You did good.
Yeah. Well, actually,
it's a complete disaster, but thanks.
Not yet.
Lewis?
What? What are you doing down here?
Actually, no. This is good.
You sent a rescue team into the mines
for Grant and Sattler?
Yeah. What? Okay. Of course. Yeah.
- Are you deleting research files?
- Uh, we are. Yes.
You and I got to protect
what we've built, right?
You think they wouldn't love
to get their hands in here?
Take all the resources
I've spent decades collecting.
Just because, what?
We made a bad call? It happens.
Seven.
Hexapod Allies.
What? Oh.
Okay. What do people know?
The locusts were designed to spread
genetic modifications to crops.
Protection against droughts,
frost, disease. A breakthrough.
- Goddamn right it was.
- Yeah. Only it didn't work.
You ensured they can't eat Biosyn seed,
so they're eating everything else.
Which I did not see coming.
We have a solution.
- Independent farmers suffered at first.
- Henry's on it.
Nobody cared much. Now the world's
food supply is verging on collapse.
Find the girl, change the locusts' DNA.
- The trail's gonna lead back to you.
- We solve the problem.
Ramsay, thank you.
Disappears in the next news cycle,
just like everything else. This is not it.
81C1.
Or you could accept responsibility.
Share your research with the world.
Yep.
You know, I was 28 once. I get it.
You look around, you...
realize you're surrounded by injustice
and cruelty and you wanna change it.
Yep.
And then you grow up,
somebody puts you in charge,
and you see that
there is no changing it.
It's chomp or be chomped.
- Where are you going with that?
- Oh.
We don't apologize for our mistakes.
We erase them.
Stay on your phone. I may need you.
Watch yourself.
- Ellie?
- Yeah.
What was that?
Be careful.
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
Forget the hat!
Come on!
Go, go, go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
There's no button.
It's a car.
- Oh, my God. Ian!
- Ian, over here!
- Help!
- Please!
- Open the gate!
- Please help us!
- Do you know the code?
- I didn't know there was gonna be a code.
I didn't know there was
gonna be a code.
Oh, my God!
The brake!
Pull the brake!
There are 10,000 possibilities.
Push your legs against it!
- 1984.
- Come on, Ian!
- Kick up against it!
- Hurry!
Miles Davis's birthday, 0526.
- Ian!
- Please. Please.
- Do something!
- We're not gonna make it.
Let's-- Let's all try to stay positive.
- Please!
- I know. I know. I know!
Oh, my God!
What do you know?
It actually worked.
- Ian, this is Maisie.
- Hi, Maisie.
We got the DNA.
- We need to get out of this valley.
- Yeah.
- Come on. Come on.
- Let's go. Let's go.
Come on. Come on.
Go on. Get!
Yuck.
Hey.
Oh, my God.
I thought you were dead.
What do they even eat?
We better get inside.
Go ahead.
Containment chamber compromised.
It's locked.
Gonna need something heavy,
something sharp, or both.
That can't be right.
- Is that...
- Oh, no.
Oh, my God.
He's burning the evidence.
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God! Oh, my--
- That's bananas.
Oh, my God.
I-- I know that
this may seem precarious, but...
No, we're teetering.
Shouldn't we all lean
to the left or something?
That's a very constructive--
Thank you, Maisie.
Yeah.
Slow. Slow.
Slow.
Yay.
- We're fine. See this?
- Mm-hmm.
- This is fine.
Alan?
Alan!
How is everybody?
It's my parents.
Help!
- Help!
- Listen.
Help!
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
You're okay.
You came to get me. You actually--
You came to get me.
Of course we did, sweetheart.
- Hey.
- Of course.
I remember you.
Remember you too.
They helped me escape.
Yeah?
You okay?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
We gotta go.
Gonna have to break a window
to get inside that thing.
Hope nobody is afraid of heights.
- Don't move.
What is that?
Giganotosaurus.
Biggest carnivore
the world has ever seen.
Maisie, Maisie.
Look at me. Look at me.
Go.
- Go, go, go.
- Come on!
No! No, no, no.
- Hustle!
- I'm gonna die!
- Climb! Climb, kid!
- No!
You're not. No, you're not.
You're okay.
Go, go, go.
Come on.
Hey!
Oh, yeah. Come here.
Help me open it.
I got ya.
Go, go, go.
Go, go, go!
Run!
See? Not so bad.
Come on.
- Owen!
- Claire!
Call an evacuation.
We need to bring the animals inside.
The regulations are clear
that in the event of a level two--
Shh!
Jeffrey.
God--
Damn it!
Just--
Just call it.
Attention, attention.
This is an immediate evacuation order.
Remote herding system is now active.
All living assets en route
to emergency containment.
I can't get hold of anybody
since everything is on fire.
- Dr. Sattler, get some water.
- Oh, thanks.
Dr. Grant?
Here you are.
I'm Owen Grady.
Big fan. I read your book.
Well, book on tape.
Owen Grady. Owen Grady.
Yeah, I know who you are.
You trained raptors.
I tried. Yeah.
- How you doing?
- The one here.
You were at Jurassic World.
Jurassic World? Not a fan.
Mm-mmm.
Okay.
So, we good to find a way out of here?
- Yep.
- Let's get it.
There's a helicopter
out in the main complex.
We turn the ADS back on, we go home.
- Wait. What's an ADS?
- Aerial Deterrent System.
You know?
For the pterodactyls and shit.
Keeps them away from the helicopters.
Well, how do we turn it back on?
It looks like all the systems
run through to the control room,
which is on the third floor.
These outposts are all
connected underground.
All right. Easy, Rambo.
So you worked in the raptor pen, huh?
Yeah.
Wow. And what happens?
Do you just tell them what to do
and they comply? Or...
Well, it's a human-animal bond
based on mutual respect.
Mm-hmm.
I had a dog once.
Humped my leg so much
I got a callus on my shinbone.
That's a true story.
Oh, God. Hey. Good.
Here's what I'm thinking.
We get started again.
You and me.
I can get money.
Yeah. Money's cheap these days.
Wh-What's the matter?
Don't look so worried. There's--
There's opportunity in everything.
E-Even this. You'll learn that.
I've been thinking,
maybe you take more of a lead now. Okay?
You're ready, I think.
Here, take--
What the hell is the matter with you?
It was you.
You told Malcolm about the program.
Y-You--
You set this whole thing up.
You set me up.
I gave you every opportunity
I did not have. I--
We have an understanding, Ramsay.
And you do not break that.
I would not break this.
I'm not you.
Uh-oh.
This is very bad.
This is the same system
we used at the park.
Great. So we can turn on the thing
and then we all get out of here?
Let's see. ADS...
What's this? What's "Error 99"?
Not enough power.
In a breakdown,
all available power is seized
by the primary system to keep running.
We need all that power
to reactivate the ADS.
The system's safety feature
is what's gonna kill us?
Of course.
- How do we get more power?
- We can't.
But we can redistribute what we have.
- Just need to...
- Shut down the primary system.
- Yes. Exactly.
- Where is it?
- Uh, next floor up.
- I'm coming with you.
We escaped down here.
- Where is that? Water treatment center?
- Hydroelectric system. Sub eight.
Give me eight minutes.
I could find her.
Wait. Who's this now?
Beta. Blue's baby.
Velociraptor.
- What?
- A baby raptor?
You gave her a name.
How about that?
I made a promise
we would bring her home.
You made a promise to a dinosaur.
You're coming with us, right?
Maisie, I--
Please.
- I'll be on channel five.
- Okay.
We're on three.
Come back.
I always come back.
I'll have that chopper hot in ten.
Wait for my signal.
Evacuation phase four complete.
All living assets now in containment.
Come on.
Still get nightmares?
All the time.
You?
I have a lot of regrets.
Oh, yeah?
Well,
we hold on to regret,
we stay in the past.
What matters, I guess, is--
is what we do now.
- Right?
- Yeah.
Ah.
Okay.
Nobody said there'd be bugs.
B4. She's in here.
Watch the sides.
They always come from the sides.
You know, at first we thought
they disembowel their prey, but no.
They're smart enough
to go straight for the throat.
The veins, the arteries.
Sometimes both at the same time.
Okay.
We've got you.
It's right down that aisle.
It's right down that aisle
where you are.
Why are they skulking in--
You can sprint right for it.
Okay. Here it is.
Okay, it'll be a yellow button
on a grid of six.
There's a green button.
Do you see a green button?
It's not that green button.
It's four from the bottom.
Above this--
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Fourth one up?
Third one down or fourth one up.
Same thing.
Ian, be specific.
She was here.
Lights off.
I don't know how I could
possibly be more specific
other than to say that
the one you want is marked
- with "E1." E1.
- E1.
E1.
Yeah.
No. No, no, no, no.
Damn it. She's fast.
Hey!
Eyes on me.
I've got to hit her
on the side of her neck.
Maisie, you're gonna hold her focus.
Grant,
we're triangulating.
Go.
Sorry, girl.
I promised your mom I'd get you home.
Primary system rebooting.
Wait. Oh, no, no, no.
- No, no, no.
- It's rebooting.
It shouldn't be doing that.
Here, take this.
- Gonna stay on it.
- Shut it down!
We're gonna make it work.
We're gonna figure this out. It's complex.
We don't have time for complex!
Primary system compromised.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Aerial Deterrent System active.
Victory. Victory.
Damn, that felt good.
Oh! Come on!
What's your story?
Wait!
At Biosyn, we're dedicated to the idea
that dinosaurs can teach us
more about ourselves.
All right, Kayla. We're good to go.
Okay, cutie.
Come here.
You all right?
- Someday.
- Okay.
Hey.
I remember you.
Please. You have to listen to me.
You created an ecological disaster.
And I can fix it.
Charlotte Lockwood changed
every cell in Maisie's body.
It saved her life.
If I can understand how
Charlotte rewrote Maisie's DNA,
I can spread change from
one locust to the entire swarm.
Before it's too late.
It's okay.
It's what she would've wanted.
Thank you.
No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Him?
Not him. Not him.
It's always him.
Every si--
Is that a dinosaur on your shoulder?
Yeah. Why?
I have air. Meet me at the center.
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
Hey, hey. Do not land in here.
I don't have a choice, dude.
The valley isn't safe.
No, they're not in the valley anymore!
Oh!
This isn't about us.
Go! Go!
Come on!
Oh, my God! Get him up!
Come on, come on!
Come on.
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on!
Ellie, no!
Come on, Maisie! Go!
Ramsay, get in.
Come on, come on, come on.
Everybody hold on to somebody.
Ow.
No, at every level.
Complete systemic corruption
in the executive ranks.
"Systemic corruption." You get that?
Write that down.
Yeah, it's crazy.
And then-- And then we crashed
into this ice lake, right?
I mean,
they literally owe me a plane.
I need to get this sample vetted
at the lab
before I take it to my contact
at the Times.
You could, uh, come with me.
Unless you need
to get back to your dig.
- Ellie?
- Yeah?
I am coming with you.
I know. One more minute,
then we'll send you home with your folks.
Today marks the first day of testimony
from Biosyn whistleblower Ramsay Cole.
The Senate will also hear from
Doctors Grant, Sattler and Malcolm,
who have been vocal in this debate
since the incident at Jurassic Park.
You look...
- Uncomfortable.
- ...trustworthy.
Yeah, not getting used to it.
Let's finish this.
Yeah.
Dr. Henry Wu has found
an emergency solution
to the ecological crisis.
His use of a pathogen
to alter the locusts' DNA
has revolutionized modern genetics.
He attributed the discovery
to another scientist, Charlotte Lockwood,
who died nearly 13 years ago.
By UN decree, Biosyn valley
has been designated a global sanctuary.
The animals will live there free,
safe from the outside world.
- Money?
- Money.
Thank you.
Life on Earth has existed
for hundreds of millions of years.
And dinosaurs were only a part of that.
And we're an even smaller part of that.
They really put us in perspective.
The idea that life on Earth
existed 65 million years ago...
it's humbling.
We act like we're alone here,
but we're not.
We're part of a fragile system
made up of all living things.
If we're going to survive,
we'll have to trust each other.
Depend on each other.
Coexist.